# VAIBHAV SONI

+918302665842

vssonivaibhav6@gmail.com vaibhavsoni.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am a software professional with more than 7 years of professional experience in designing, developing and delivering software applications and products. I have worked on a range of technologies from C++ application development to Javascript based web applications.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2022 - present (Remote)

Pharmeasy

Launched in 2015, PharmEasy is pharmacy made easy! Started with the sole purpose of making healthcare accessible and affordable to all, PharmEasy today is India's leading and most trusted online healthcare aggregator in the country.

Consumer Growth Team - Role: Associate Technical Architect

- ✓ Worked with a team of 15 people day to day activities involved Design, develop, refactor, current architecture, brainstorming new solution with business and developers, manage implementation and deliveries, PR reviews etc.
- ✓ Optimized user segment service to serve 40% more traffic.
- ✓ Helped team to identify bottlenecks and optimize syncing large datasets bringing down time from 4-5 days to 5 hours
- ✓ Helped team optimize discount service to support faster and larger uploads of the file with discount details bringing uploads time from 3 hours to 1/2 hr.
- ✓ Led infra spearhead activity with the team which helped the team reduce ~20% infra cost, also trained to identify and measure correct resource requirements using tools like grafana Prometheus and AWS metrics
- ✓ Co-Architected Offer content discovery System
- ✓ Led activity to identify various nonuser path matrices for services and set up important alerts and slack notifications
- Coordinated with other teams to architect and develop various features
- Responsible for translating business need to technical requirements and brainstorming solutions and helping to implement and deliver the same

Oct 2020 - April 2022 (Remote)

Alepo

Alepo makes next-generation data opportunities a reality, creating advanced software solutions and services that enable global communications service providers to accelerate revenue growth, market share, and business success on fixed and mobile broadband networks.

R&D 5g team - Role: Technical Architect

- ✓ Responsible for evaluating and benchmarking and creating POCs of different technologies which could be a possible fit in current ecosystem or provide better performance. Some of the technologies evaluated are Kafka, sonarqube, sso engines, confluence plugins, document generating tools like swagger etc.
- ✓ Wrote a matching engine in Lua
- ✓ Lead a team of 2 developers to test & integrate matching engine with existing products

- Developed an Fault manager and KPI collector microservices in nodejs which acts like a bridge between different alerting system like Prometheus and existing microservices
- ✓ Co-Architected Licensing server for 5g Products
- ✓ Architected and developed Configuration manager using nodejs and ETCD
- ✓ Worked on 5g PCF (Policy Function Control) development implemented in nodejs and angular
- ✓ Lead a team of 4 people to Test & Release various components of product to clients
- ✓ Interacted with clients for integrating our products with their systems

Xooa empowers users of all blockchain expertise levels to build NFT marketplaces and other blockchain apps on the cloud fast through a streamlined and easy-to-use interface.

Dev Team - Role: Team lead

- Responsible for hiring for dev roles and providing them a seamless onboarding with current codebase
- ✓ Helped teams clearing technical backlogs, and made product more stable
- ✓ Helped build a team from scratch to Ramp up Product development.
- Leading and Managing Team of 7 Developers responsible for developing various NFT marketplace features
- Connecting with clients to resolve their product related queries and gather future development requirements
- Creating technical requirements for features and managing sprints
- ✓ Distributing Jira tickets and helping team with day to day operations
- Developed self-serve capabilities which allowed users to configure and operated various aspects of product seamlessly.
- ✓ Developed various products plugins like Wailtlist , Customisable carousels etc
- Responsible for code quality and PR reviews

Oct 2018 - Sept 2020

Xtreme Blockchain Labs(Now acquired by kognitiv)

Xtreme Blockchain Labs created a Cryptocurrency exchange which helps users to trade cryptocurrencies like BTC , ETH , LTC etc for Canadian nationalists.

- Build a custom logger node module to create logs in defined format and to be pushed to Elasticsearch.
- ✓ Build A tracking system to track communication between microservices. includes developing 2 node modules to track Rest calls and one to track messages from redis kue.
- ✓ Enhanced Testing by writing test cases in MochaJs, ChaiJs
- ✓ Created Kibana Dashboards for the tracking systems;
- Created microservice to fanout data from Trade Data aggregators to different sockets to plot Candlestick charts and manage historical data with influx db(time series database).
- ✓ Created a streaming microservice framework for node & kafka stream
- Created Ethereum based smart contracts in solidity for some POCs.
- Created Artillery scripts to load test and benchmark for trades in trade engine.
- ✓ Helped team by actively reviewing code and creating curd based features for various use cases across the other microservices like trading engine, kyc, wallted management etc.
- ✓ Involved with various Design discussions and decisions.
- ✓ Lead a team of 3 (2 Dev , 1 QA) for delivering ethirum based POCs.

Feb 2017 - Oct 2018

Apiria (Now acquired by jupiter.money)

Apiria is a virtual assistant for modern age employees. A significant amount of productive time is spent by an employee on performing mundane and repetitive activity on a HR portal. Apiria is that

'smart' system which not only shows relevant information but also performs automated tasks to increase employee productivity.

- ✓ Leading the HRMS team of 10 (7 Dev , 3 QA) and helping team with Coding Practices and Agile Methodologies
- ✓ Build a workflow Application from scratch using Reactjs, Nodejs, Graphql, Mongodb.
- ✓ Leading and Managing Team of 3 dev responsible for developing and delivering future versions of workflow Application
- Worked on developing api-servers for supporting application's frontend using rest api's and graphql.
- ✓ Wrote Payroll Engine which was able to calculate taxes as per Indian laws
- Enhanced Testing by writing test cases in MochaJs and automating tasks using Grunt
- Designed and developed features which would help user to setup the application in various modes
- ✓ Designed and developed various features like Expense Management System for the application
- ✓ Developed Frontend in Angularis for the various feature of the application
- Actively played role in appraisal cycles, manage hirings and on-boarding of fresh recruits

#### Aug 2016 – Feb 2017

#### Cantern

Cantern is an educational analytics company, they enable colleges to enhance their profile and students' employability through the power of data, aggregate the data from various sources and employ a series of algorithms to understand and convert the raw data to useful insights for the college.

- ✓ Worked on developing product from scratch which includes Dashboard and different servers
- ✓ Worked on developing Reporting framework using of Phantom Js , Nodejs ,MongoDb ,Expressjs
- ✓ Have Also worked on Charting and graph libraries like Morris is , Plottable is , C3 is etc .
- ✓ Developed various in house tools to make download and modify reports
- ✓ Lead a team 4 (3 dev , 1 content writer) for achieving Legacy platform stability
- Mentored the team to successful releases within a short span of time.
- Responsible for timely releases to the customer

#### Oct 2015 – Aug 2016

EroNkan Technologies Private Limited,

Eronkan provides various IIOT services to enterprises. I have worked on the core product features and also internal tools. The technology stack that I was involved in consisted of Node JS and EmberJS.

- ✓ Responsible for maintaining beta version of the product on an ec2 instances which include updating source code, regularly test new features etc.
- ✓ Worked on building a monitoring system which keep check on driver's status installed on client's system.
- ✓ Worked on automation of server related task using monit, upstart and shell scripts.
- ✓ Worked on various customizations of frontend templates to fulfil client requirements.
- ✓ Worked on developing various api used for various features in the framework, developed using various tools like redis, rabbitmq, sqs etc.
- ✓ Worked on developing alerting systems which uses sms, mails to send alert to customers in case of various client defined situations.
- ✓ Have also made many clients visit where I was responsible to fetch data from FANUC CNC machine using RS232 ports.

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript , Nodejs , AngularJs, Angular8+ ,Ionic 4 , Reactjs , Mochajs , Graphql, HTML, CSS, Team management , Project management ,PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, Rabbitmq, Linux, AWS SQS, Kafka , Monit, git ,ACE editor, Bootstrap, Processing, Knexjs , Server-Administration etc.

## OTHER COURSES

- ✓ Introduction to Computational Arts (University Of New York Online).
- ✓ HTML5.1x: Web Design Fundamentals (Part 1) (Through edx.org by W3C)

## INTERNSHIP/TRAINING

✓ Girnar Technologies Pvt ltd Jaipur .

## **WORKSHOPS & SEMINARS**

- ✓ Ethical Hacking 1.0 & lab by i3indya Technologies at Neuron 12 MNIT Jaipur on 4th Nov 2012.
- ✓ NEN Entrepreneur Workshop Held at college campus.
- ✓ Attended Infosys Campus Connect workshops held at college

## **EDUCATION**

2015	<b>Bachelor of Technology</b> (RTU) (Computer Science) Poornima Institute Of Engineering And Technology Jaipur, Rajasthan, India
2010	<b>Higher Secondary Certificate</b> (12 <sup>th</sup> ) (CBSE),Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India
2008	Secondary School Certificate(10 <sup>th</sup> ) (CBSE),Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India